Guide to the K.C Parsons publications collection, 1915-1999
Parsons, K.C. publications, 1915-1999
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
K.C. Parsons publications collection, 1915-1999
6691
K. C. (Kermit Carlyle) Parsons
8 cubic feet
Publications, Reports, Maps/Charts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes publications, published and unpublished ralating to urban planning issues and various national building projects.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of architecture, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes publications, published and unpublished ralating to urban planning issues and various national building projects.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Parsons, Kermit, C. (Kermit Carlyle), 1927,; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
City planning.; Architecture--Study and teaching.; City planners.; Architects.; Building--Research--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series: eastern US
  - Comprehensive plan report consisting of the official comprehensive plan and comprehensive plan supplement: Cranston, Rhode Island, June 1961 (Box 6)
    Created by Blair Associates
    Prepared for City Plan Commission. Foldout map in back.
  - Master plan for Norwood neighborhood, city of Warwick, July 1997 (Box 6)
    Created by Cecil & Rizvi, Inc.; Vanasse Hangen Brustlin Inc.
    Prepared for Norwood Neighborhood Association
  - Master plan for Oakland Beach, city of Warwick, May 1995 (Box 8)
    Prepared for Oakland Beach Association
  - Plan for recreation and open space: a part of the master plan for Cranston, Rhode Island, September 1960 (Box 6)
    Prepared for City Plan Commission
  - East Cambridge riverfront plan, May 1978 (Box 6)
    Created by City of Cambridge Community Development Department
  - Government Center progress report, May 1964 (Box 6)
    Created by Boston Redevelopment Authority
  - Toward a sustainable future: Cambridge growth policy document (final draft), February 1993 (Box 6)
    Created by Cambridge Planning Board and Community Development Department
  - Community development plan: guidelines for restoring the townscape of Charlestown, 1990s? (Box 6)
    Created by CBT/Childs Bertman Tseckares & Casendino Inc.
    Contains artist's rendering map.
  - Campus physical master plan: University of Massachusetts Amherst, August 1993 (Box 6)
    Created by Jack Ahern, Mark Lindhult, and John Mullin
    Contains Xeroxed copy of "A View to the Future: Facilities Planning and the University of Massachusetts Boston", June 1995
  - Master plan for land use: East Providence, Rhode Island (publication number 4, master plan reports), June 1962 (Box 6)
    Created by East Providence Planning Board and Department of Planning
  - The greater Hartford process, April 1972 (Box 6)
    Created by The American City Corporation
  - The master plan--Providence, Rhode Island: a guide to development to the year 1975, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Created by Providence City Plan Commission
  - The Boston contest of 1944: prize winning programs (Box 6)
    Created by The Boston Contest
  - 1965-1975 general plan for the city of Boston and the regional core, November 1964 (Box 7)
  - Weybosset Hill: Providence, Rhode Island, March 1963 (Box 7)
    Created by I.M. Pei & Associates
    Prepared for the Providence Redevelopment Agency
  - Master plan for Pontiac Village: City of Warwick, Rhode Island, April 1995 (Box 7)
    Created by Cecil & Rizvi, Inc.; Vanasse Hangen Brustlin, Inc
    Prepared for the Pontiac Village Association
  - Redevelopment and renewal plan for the Church Street project area: New Haven, Connecticut, June 1957 (Box 7)
    Created by City of New Haven Redevelopment Agency
  - Conceptual master plan for East Natick Village: Warwick, Rhode Island, May 1995 (Box 7)
    Created by Albert Veri & Associates, Inc.
  - A comprehensive plan of development for Farmington, Connecticut, 1964 (Box 7)
    Created by Town of Farmington Planning Department
    Foldout map in back pocket
  - Inventory survey for the city of Attleboro, Massachusetts, July 1960 (Box 7)
  - City of Pawtucket comprehensive plan 1995 (Box 7)
    Created by City Planning Commission
    Copy number 85
  - Industrial potential of the southeastern Massachusetts planning region, February 1958 (Box 7)
  - Commercial areas study: a study prepared for the city of Cranston, Rhode Island, November 1960 (Box 7)
    Created by Cranston City Plan Commission; Blair Associates
  - Tomorrow is here: New New New Haven, Connecticut, 1944 (Box 7)
    Created by City Plan Commission
  - Report on land use: Camden County, New Jersey, June 1961 (Box 7)
    Created by Camden County Planning Board
  - Dixwell redevelopment and renewal plan [amended], April 1965 (Box 7)
    Created by New Haven Redevelopment Agency
  - Downtown Providence 1970: special report, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Illustrative site plan: Charlestown urban renewal area, Massachusetts R-55 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Large foldout map poster; looks to be part of a report.
  - Southwest corridor development plan: Boston Massachusetts, Fall 1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Created by MBTA
    Large foldout map poster
  - A report from the town plan of Stratford, Connecticut, March 1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Created by Fairfield County Planning Association
  - Alternatives for a regional plan of development, November 1961 (Box 7)
    Created by Capitol Region Planning Agency (Connecticut)
    701 Project: Connecticut P-14
  - Inventory survey for the town of North Attleborough, Massachusetts, March 1962 (Box 7)
    Created by Blair and Stein Associates
- Series: General
  - Intergovernmental action on environmental policy: the role of the states, February 1967 (Box 8)
    Created by Deil S. Wright
    No. II in series Environmental Studies, ed. Lynton K. Caldwell
  - Economic aspects of housing for the aged, 1961 (Box 8)
    Created by Glenn H. Beyer
    Research report no. 4, Center for Housing and Environmental Studies, Cornell University
  - Housing in metropolitan areas: roles and responsibilities of five key actors, 1973 (Box 8)
    Created by Mary K. Nenno
    National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials
  - PUD: a better way for the suburbs, 1971 (Box 8)
    Created by Maxwell C. Huntoon, Jr
    Urban Land Institute. Tucked inside is reprint of "P.U.D. is Good for Everybody", House and Home 1969, distributed by Rahenkamp Sachs Wells and Associates, Inc.
  - Planned-unit development with a homes association, 1964 (Box 8)
    Created by Federal Housing Administration
    Land Planning Bulletin No. 6; FHA No. 1097
  - Council of planning librarians exchange bibliography (series), 1968
    Created by Mary Vance, ed.
    Nos. 38 - 57. In binder.
- Series: International
  - Greater Bangkok plan: 2533, 1960 (Box 5)
    Created by Litchfield Whiting Bowne and Associates
    Personally inscribed to CRP by Tavon Pollachom, Bangkok 2/28/66
  - The Development of satellite towns in the Bangkok region and aspects of metropolitan planning, November 1965 (Box 5)
    Created by H.A. Hosse
  - Kota Raya new community, February 1984 (Box 3)
    Created by Huszar Brammah and Associates in association with Ove Arup dan Rakan Rakan
    Prepared for Hiew Fook Realty (Holdings) Sdn Bhd, Sabah (Malaysia?)
  - Metropolitan Lagos, April 1964 (Box 3)
    Created by Otto Koenigsberger, Charles Abrams, Susumu Kobe, Maurice Shapiro and Michael Wheeler
    "Prepared for the Ministry of Lagos Affairs of the Government of Nigeria by a group of experts appointed under the United Nations Technical Assistance Programme"
  - Feasibility study for sites and services, residential upgrading in Bauchi and Gombe, Nigeria: Volume 3 of 3 (Working Papers), November 1978 (Box 3)
    Created by Dar Al-Handasah Consultants (Shair and Partners)
    Government of Bauchi State, Nigeria; Bauchi State Development Board; World Bank: Nigerian States Urban Development Programme. Working Paper 10. Draft final report. Copy.
  - Esfahan, Iran master plan report, January 1961 (Box 3)
    Created by F.H. Kocks, Friedrich Pfeil, Peter von Bohr
    "Edited and published by United States Operations Mission to Iran, Public Administration Division."
  - Centro urbano insurgentes Ticoman (Box 3)
    Created by ?
    Spiral-bound copies of plans.
  - Desarrollo urbano: sistema normative de equipamiento urbano normas basicas, October 1981 (Box 3)
    Created by Secretaria de asentamientos humanos y obras publicas
    Mexico
  - Fundametos de proyecto mercados municipales. Gerencia de obras: asesoria tecnica de edificios (Box 3)
    Created by Grupo Banobras
  - Basic development plan: Calcutta metropolitan district, 1966-1986 (Box 3)
    Created by Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Organisation
  - A renewal programme for the city of Waterford, November 1968 (Box 3)
    Created by David W. Cronin and Anthony M. O Neill
    Commissioned by An Foras Forbartha in cooperation with Waterford Corporation (Ireland)
  - The municipality of metropolitan Toronto, 1965, July 1965 (Box 3)
    Created by Metropolitan Toronto Planning Board
  - Proposed plan for Toronto, June 1967 (Box 3)
    Created by The City of Toronto Planning Board
    Includes "Letter of Transmittal" inserted in document
  - Plan for downtown Toronto: a report by the City of Toronto Planning Board 1963 (Box 3)
  - Report on the Metropolitan Toronto transportation plan, December 1964 (Box 3)
  - Official plan of the Metropolitan Toronto planning area, December 1965 (Box 3)
    Includes land use plan in pocket
  - Official plan of the Metropolitan Toronto planning area: supplement, December 1965 (Box 3)
    Includes existing land use plan map in pocket
  - Master plan: Ville Marie Montreal, March 1967 (Box 3)
    Created by I.M. Pei and Associates
    A report to the officers and directors of the Canadian National Railway Company by Webb&Knapp (Canada) Limited
  - Elements of a city plan for Cornwall, Ontario, Canada, April 1944 (Box 3)
    Created by Wilson & Bunnell
  - A plan and recommended program for the transformation of the Nemesio R. Canales public housing project, San Juan metropolitan area, Puerto Rico, February 1967 (Box 3)
    Created by Urban Renewal and Housing Administration
  - Ponce metropolitan area: progress report of the transportation planning process 1964-1971 (Box 3)
    Created by Commonwealth of Puerto Rico Highway Authority Planning Office
  - Ponce general neighborhood renewal plan: north central section, July 1966 (Box 3)
    Created by Puerto Rico Urban Renewal and Housing Administration
  - Mayaguez metropolitan area progress report of the transportation planning process, 1964-1971 (Box 3)
  - El Polvorin: a case study (Box 3)
    Created by Puerto Rico Urban Renewal and Housing Corporation
    Rehabilitation in place program
  - Harlow expansion survey: a report to the Ministry of Housing & Local Government on the possibility of expanding Harlow, March 1963 (Box 3)
    Created by Harlow Development Corporation
    Includes map in front pocket; "Harlow" (reprint from The Architect and Building News July 3, 1952); brochure from "Festival of Britain: Harlow New Town Exhibition", May-September 1951
  - Plan for Taunton, March 1948 (Box 3)
    Created by Thomas Sharp
    Includes map in back pocket
  - Hatfield New Town, October 1949 (Box 3)
    Created by Hatfield Development Corporation
    Report of the Hatfield Development Corporation as submitted to the Minister of Town and County Planning upon the outline plan prepared by Lionel Brett, M.A., A.R.I.B.A. Includes map in back pocket.
  - Greater Peterborough master plan, 1970 (Box 3)
    Created by Peterborough Development Corporation
    Foldout structure map attached in back
  - York Region official plan, 1998 (Box 3)
    Created by Regional Municipality of York
    Office consolidation (as of July 1, 1998)
  - Saint-Die (Box 3)
    Report presentation pasted into folder; no identifying info.
  - Planning for development: the Capital region, September 1975 (Box 3)
    Created by Town and Country Planning Division, Ministry of Planning & Development, Government of Trinidad & Tobago
    Development Planning Series No. T1/2/3. Draft. Several foldout maps attached in back.
- Series: Midwest
  - Suburban business centers: an inventory, analysis and projection of outer urban and suburban business centers in metropolitan Cleveland - Technical supplement, September 1961 (Box 4)
    Created by Regional Planning Commission
  - Our downtown parking headache and how we can cure it: Cleveland downtown parking survey preliminary report, 1951 (Box 4)
    Created by Cleveland City Planning Commission
  - Ohio Architect, February 1962 (Box 4)
    Created by Architects Society of Ohio
    Official publication of the Architects Society of Ohio. Volume XX, No. 2
  - A sector of a metropolis: a study of radial corridor development for the Chicago metropolitan region, 1964 (Box 4)
    Created by University of Illinois, Urbana
    A project by graduate students in architecture and city planning at the University of Illinois
  - Council Grove: historic conservation, May 1975 (Box 4)
    Created by Kansas State University College of Architecture and Design
    A collective effort by Departments of Pre-Design Professions; Landscape Architecture; Architecture
  - Environs study and plan: Detroit metropolitan Wayne County airport, May 1964 (Box 4)
    Created by Detroit Metropolitan Area Regional Planning Commission
  - Comprehensive plan: Dayton urban area, August 1954 (Box 4)
    Created by Harland Bartholomew and Associates
    Prepared for the City Plan Board, Dayton, Ohio. Includes map in back pocket.
  - Detroit suburban planning, May 1915 (Box 4)
    Created by Arthur Coleman Comey
    Report to the city plan and improvement commission based on the preliminary plan for Detroit by Edward H. Bennett, architect
  - Selecting urban renewal projects: some proposed policies, November 1956 (Box 4)
    Created by City Planning Board of Saint Paul, MN
    Community Plan Report Number 3, publication number 103
  - The proposed freeways for Saint Paul, June 1957 (Box 4)
    Community Plan Report Number 4, publication number 104
  - Proposed planning districts with significant background data for planning, August 1957 (Box 4)
    Community Plan Report Number 5, publication number 105
  - Saint Paul's preliminary land use plan, July 1959 (Box 4)
    Community Plan Report Number 8
  - The corridor concept: implications for Illinois, 1967-68 (Box 4)
    A study carried out by second-year graduate students in the Department of Urban Planning at the University of Illinois, Urbana
  - Lake Meadows: a complete residential community on Chicago's popular Near South Side, 1970s(?) (Box 4)
    Created by Draper and Kramer, Inc.
    Advertisement, floor plans and application for apartment complex
  - Community: a right to belong - the McKinley Neighborhood, Muncie, Indiana, December 1989 (Box 4)
    Created by James M. Riggs
    Report for PLAN 301, Department of Urban Planning, Ball State University. Includes photos of Powerpoint presentation
  - Strategy'91: GUEA/Lilly strategic planning final report, December 1991 (Box 4)
    Created by Gary Urban Enterprise Association
  - The proposed central business district circulation system, January 1957 (Box 4)
    Created by City Planning Commission, Cincinnati OH
    Part One of the Central Business District Plan
  - Design standards: central business district no. 1, Ohio R-81, Youngstown OH, November 1970 (Box 4)
    Created by William A. Gould and Associates
  - A master plan for the Fourth Street Area, January 1966 (Box 4)
    Created by Samuel V. Noe
    Includes letter to KC Parsons from Pistler Brown Architecture with personal note from Bill Brown
  - The comprehensive plan of Chicago, December 1966 (Box 4)
    Created by Department of Development and Planning
  - Development plan for northeast Youngstown, September 1962 (Box 4)
    Prepared for the City Planning Commission, Youngstown OH
  - The redevelopment of Kenyon Barr for industrial use: a preliminary report, July 1955 (Box 4)
    Created by Office of the City Manager, Cincinnati, Ohio
  - The Cincinnati metropolitan master plan and the official city plan, 1948 (Box 4)
    Includes large master plan map and report, "For Students Interested in a Career in City Planning" by the City Planning Commission, 1963
  - Ohio City-Central Park West: technical report on a preliminary plan for the future development of the area, April 1958 (Box 4)
    Created by Klein and Hodne Associates
    Prepared for the Ohio City Planning Sponsors, Ohio City Center Planning Project
  - Comprehensive city plan for Cedar Rapids, Iowa, 1931 (Box 4)
    Prepared for the City Plan Commission. Includes map
  - A comprehensive city plan for Dayton, OH: Chapters IV-V-VI-VII, 1926 (Box 4)
    Created by Technical Advisory Corporation
    Prepared for the City Plan Board
  - Ohio City Center-Central Park West: economic analysis and report, July 1958 (Box 4)
    Created by Charles D. Laidlaw
  - Lower Hill, Pittsburgh, 1959 (Box 4)
    A Webb & Knapp Project
  - The general plan of Cleveland: an address by John T. Howard, 1949 (Box 4)
    Created by John T. Howard
    Publication Number 21, Regional Association of Cleveland
  - Madison's land: how it is used, September 1952 (Box 4)
    Created by City Plan Commission, Madison, Wisconsin
  - East 131 St. & Miles retail district plan, August 1991 (Box 4)
    Created by Gould Associates Inc.
    For the Cleveland City Planning Commission
  - Revised city plan: city of Hamilton, Ohio, July 1948 (Box 4)
    Prepared for the City Plan Commission, Hamilton, Ohio
  - Downtown York, 1971 (Box 4)
    Created by The Pennsylvania State University, Department of Architecture
    Prepared under the direction of Lawrence Regan, Assistant Professor of Architecture and Urban Design, with the following student architects
  - Kansas City - 1980, 1957 (Box 4)
    Created by Kansas City Chapter of the American Institute of Architects
    A "civic project"
  - Development framework: policy, plan, program, 1975(?) (Box 4)
    Created by Metropolitan Council, St. Paul MN
    Chapter of the Minnesota Development Guide
  - The Detroit medical center: a proposal for the re-use of land cleared under the Federal and City Urban Renewal Program, September 1958 (Box 4)
    Created by Detroit Medical Center Citizens Committee
    Includes board of model
  - Cleveland Civic Vision 2000: citywide plan, 1991 (Box 4)
    FAL reference reserve copy
  - Central Gary: 1980: central business district redevelopment plan, 1960-1980, March 1959 (Box 4)
    Created by Cornell University Department of City and Regional Planning
    A report prepared by graduate students in the Department of City and Regional Planning
- Series: New York City
  - Roosevelt Island: Manhattan's other island, 1970s (Box 2)
    Created by New York State Urban Development Corporation
    advertisement
  - Urban renewal, 1958 (Box 2)
    Created by New York City Planning Commission
    West Side urban renewal study
  - Kips Bay Plaza: Webb & Knapp's newest residential community (Box 2)
    Created by
    Advertisement & floor plan
  - Harlem, the next 10 years: A proposal for discussion, June 1974 (Box 2)
    Created by Harlem Urban Development Corporation
    Report of the Harlem Task Force
  - Lower Manhattan recommended land use redevelopment areas and traffic improvements: 1st report, 1958 (Box 2)
    Created by Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association Inc.
  - West Side urban renewal area: preliminary plan, 1959 (Box 2)
    Created by Urban Renewal Board, City of New York
  - Lincoln Square slum clearance plan, under Title 1 of the Housing Act of 1949 as amended, May 1956 (Box 2)
    Created by Committee on Slum Clearance
    Includes newspaper clipping, "Role of Fordham in Project Upheld"
  - The structure of planning in the New York metropolitan region, September 1966 (Box 2)
    Created by Dennis A. Rondinelli
    Copy of master's thesis, Cornell University, Department of City and Regional Planning
  - The village in the city, 1961 (?) (Box 2)
    Created by The Lavanburg Foundation
    Advertisement brochure
  - Morningside Heights, October 1959 (Box 2)
    Created by Morningside Heights, Inc.
    Proposal for reclamation program
  - New York City housing planning development agency: organization charts (Box 2)
    Created by New York City Housing Planning Development Agency
    Includes 2 maps
  - Relocation in New York City: special report to Mayor Robert F. Wagner, December 1959 (Box 2)
    Created by J. Anthony Panuch
    Mayor's Independent Survey on Housing and Urban Renewal - J. Anthony Panuch, Special Adviser
  - Building a better New York, March 1960 (Box 2)
  - The port of New York: proposals for development, September 1964 (Box 2)
    Created by City Planning Commission, Department of City Planning
    Comprehensive Planning Series No. 0164
  - Jamaica Center 1971 (Box 2)
    Created by Greater Jamaica Development Corporation
    "A progress report"
  - A report to the city of New York: an analysis of development trends and projections and recommendations for a new city in South Richmond, May 1970 (Box 2)
    Created by The Rouse Company; The American City Corporation
  - Staten Island development: policies, programs, and priorities, June 1966 (Box 2)
    Stamped "confidential"
  - Report from ACTION. Area improvement sponsored by large institutions: Morningside Heights, New York City, September 1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Created by American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods
  - Public service in older cities: a report of the second regional plan, May 1968 (Box 2)
    Created by Dick Netzer; Ralph Kaminsky; Katherine W. Strauss
    Prepared for the Regional Plan Association
- Series: Philadelphia, PA
  - "An antibiotic for the slum", 1953 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Created by American Friends Service Committee
    Reprint of NYT Magazine article by Mary Roche of October 25, 1953
  - Relationship of assessed valuation and sale price of real estate sold in 1958 with comparisons at five-year intervals, 1943-1958 (City of Philadelphia public information bulletin), July 1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Created by Philadelphia City Planning Commission
  - Analysis of proposed 1960 capital budget and 1960-1965 capital program, October 1959 (Box 7)
    Created by Citizens' Council on City Planning
    Contains "Reserve Book" library borrowing record card.
  - Schuylkill River Park: Center City Redevelopment Area, October 1964 (Box 7)
  - The 1960-65 capital program and the comprehensive plan, March 1960 (Box 7)
  - Capital program 1960-1965, November 1959 (Box 7)
  - Planning housing and redevelopment in Philadelphia: a report of the committee of urban design and housing, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Created by American Institute of Architects
  - The West Philadelphia district plan, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Eastwick, Philadelphia: a proposal to the Redevelopment Authority of the City of Philadelphia to purchase and develop all the land located in the Eastwick Redevelopment Area, 1961 (Box 8)
    Created by Doxiadis Associates, Inc.
  - Housing in Philadelphia and its metropolitan area: general characteristics and trends (public information bulletin no. 6-B), 1953 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Philadelphia does it: the battle for Penn Center", 1957 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Created by James Reichley
    Reprinted from Harper's Magazine, February 1957
  - City planning in Philadelphia, January 1944 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Contains listing of tour "Open House on Society Hill" for the American Society of Planning Officials, September 29 1954; brochure on Independence National Historical Park Project; membership invitation brochure from The Philadelphia Society for the Preservation of Landmarks; and an invitation to "A Society Hill Reception" for the 1954 National Planning Conference.